<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>platform on Mark Chmarny Blog</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/categories/platform/</link><description>Recent content in platform on Mark Chmarny Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:05:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.chmarny.com/categories/platform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How I learned Dapr building tweet sentiment processing pipeline</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/how-i-learned-dapr-building-tweet-sentiment-processing-pipeline/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:05:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/how-i-learned-dapr-building-tweet-sentiment-processing-pipeline/</guid><description>I recently joined the Office of CTO in Azure at Microsoft and wanted to ramp up on one of the open source projects the team has built there called Dapr. Dapr describes itself as:
A portable, event-driven runtime that makes it easy for developers to build resilient, microservice stateless and stateful applications that run on the cloud and edge and embraces the diversity of languages and developer frameworks.</description></item><item><title>One Platform for Your Functions, Applications, and Containers</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/one-platform-for-your-functions-apps-and-containers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 22:25:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/one-platform-for-your-functions-apps-and-containers/</guid><description>Video from the session Ville and I gave at Google Cloud Next 2018. The slides as well as the repo containing all the demos I used in this at https://github.com/mchmarny/next18</description></item><item><title>Smaller, single-purpose, atomic functions core ingredient of tomorrow’s computing</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/smaller-single-purpose-atomic-functions-core-ingredient-of-tomorrow-computing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:40:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/smaller-single-purpose-atomic-functions-core-ingredient-of-tomorrow-computing/</guid><description>Last week I had a chance to attend the 3rd AWS re:invent conference in Vegas. I’m not a big fan of that city myself, but, as in previous years, re:invent has not disappointed.
Much coverage has been dedicated to the newly introduced services; I won’t bore you with that.</description></item><item><title>PaaS not just about runtime, data services are the next differentiator</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/paas-not-just-about-runtime-data-services-are-the-next-differentiator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:30:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/paas-not-just-about-runtime-data-services-are-the-next-differentiator/</guid><description>In general, Platform as a Service (PaaS) is developed by developers for developers. Of course they’re going to love it.
It enables them to focus on the nuances of their applications — not on the day-to-day pointless activities that so often take their time away from solving real problems.</description></item></channel></rss>