<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>data on Mark Chmarny Blog</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/categories/data/</link><description>Recent content in data on Mark Chmarny Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 15:51:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.chmarny.com/categories/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using Google Cloud Spanner to measure social media influence over stock market</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/using-google-cloud-spanner-to-measure-social-media-influence-over-stock-market/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 15:51:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/using-google-cloud-spanner-to-measure-social-media-influence-over-stock-market/</guid><description>I wanted to use the now generally available Cloud Spanner database to write an app that would track stock prices and social media sentiment to identify potential correlation.
To test even the validity of this approach I put together a Go app that subscribes to Twitter stream for all companies defined in the Stocks table and scores each event against the Google NLP API while comparing the user sentiment against the stock ask price against Yahoo API.</description></item><item><title>Service, not Volume - data explosion and how to amplify its value</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/service-not-volume-data-explosion-and-how-to-amplify-its-value/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 00:46:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/service-not-volume-data-explosion-and-how-to-amplify-its-value/</guid><description>Data is growing at an exponential pace. Based on recent numbers from IDC, the total amount of data in 2015 (4.4ZB) will grow to 44ZB in 2020. Franky, how much is in Zettabyte is almost inconsequential. It is the fact that all of the data generated since the beginning of time (at least the electronic part), will grow 10x in just the next four years that’s shocking!</description></item><item><title>Data Exchange — How to Amplify Value of Machine Data</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/data-exchange-how-to-amplify-value-of-machine-data/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 13:33:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/data-exchange-how-to-amplify-value-of-machine-data/</guid><description>The presentation that goes along with this post is available here
In my last post I went over the value cycle of machine generated data. In this post, I want to follow up with a few ideas on how to further amplify value of that data by expanding its context beyond the walls of owning organization, in a construct we came to know as Data Exchange, and list a few innovation opportunities in each one of these areas.</description></item><item><title>Time series data management using InfluxDB</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/time-series-data-management-using-influxdb/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:41:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/time-series-data-management-using-influxdb/</guid><description>After a pretty positive experience with influxdb I wanted to create a super simple telemetry producer (this one in Node.js) to spotlight a few types of time series data query supported in influxdb. (Source code available on GitHub)
To get live data for this demo, I created a simple script that generates metric data for CPU Utilization and Free Memory on your local machine at 1 sec resolution.</description></item><item><title>Thinking Big about Data at Intel</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/thinking-big-about-data-at-intel/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:34:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/thinking-big-about-data-at-intel/</guid><description>I am excited to share with you today that starting Monday I will be joining the Big Data team at Intel. Yes, Intel. While not traditionally known for its software offerings, Intel has recently entered the Big Data space by introducing their own, 100% open source Hadoop distribution with unique security and monitoring features.</description></item><item><title>HDFS has won, now de facto standard for centralized data storage</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/hdfs-has-won-de-facto-standard-for-centralized-data-storage/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:28:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/hdfs-has-won-de-facto-standard-for-centralized-data-storage/</guid><description>The “high-priests” of Big Data have spoken. Hadoop Distributed File System (HDFS) is now the de facto standard platform for data storage. You may have heard this “heresy” uttered before. But, for me, it wasn’t until the recent Strata conference that I began to really understand how prevalent this opinion actually is.</description></item><item><title>Data Scientists are developers; their tools just suck</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/data-scientists-are-developers-too-their-tools-just-suck/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 03:05:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/data-scientists-are-developers-too-their-tools-just-suck/</guid><description>Data science is not a new discipline. In some sense it even pre-dates application development. You wouldn’t know that by looking at the average enterprise nowadays.
The popular perception is that enterprises today struggle to deliver any tangible value from Big Data.</description></item><item><title>Gluttony of great open ML tools too hard for enterprise to use</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/gluttony-of-open-machine-intelligence-software-enterprise-finds-hard-to-use/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 11:40:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/gluttony-of-open-machine-intelligence-software-enterprise-finds-hard-to-use/</guid><description>Seems like every week we hear about yet another new open source Machine/Deep Learning library or Analytical Framework.
Talking to people at Strata this week only confirmed for me that in the midst of what can only be described as virtual gluttony of open-source software, there is massive number of organizations who find it increasingly harder to implement these technologies.</description></item><item><title>Federated not Balkanized - The Future of Data and Its Short-term Cloud Challenges</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/federated-not-balkanized-future-of-data-and-cloud-challenges/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 00:06:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/federated-not-balkanized-future-of-data-and-cloud-challenges/</guid><description>As a long-term Cloud storage user I recently wanted to re-evaluate my options. New content management providers became available and I wanted to make sure I wasn’t missing on the new shinny tech out there.
As I was considering the pros and cons of each option, I realized the apparent shift in my personal attitude towards cloud data storage over last few years.</description></item><item><title>Data Opportunities, 3 Areas to Focus Innovation</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/data-opportunities-3-areas-to-focus-innovation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 00:33:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/data-opportunities-3-areas-to-focus-innovation/</guid><description>About a year and a half ago, I wrote about Big Data Opportunities, focusing primarily on Leveraging Unused Data, Driving New Value From Summary Data and Harnessing Heterogeneous Data Sensors (more recently known as Internet of Things).
Since that post, data space has exploded with numerous solutions addressing many of these areas.</description></item><item><title>PaaS not just about runtime, data services are the next differentiator</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/paas-not-just-about-runtime-data-services-are-the-next-differentiator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:30:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/paas-not-just-about-runtime-data-services-are-the-next-differentiator/</guid><description>In general, Platform as a Service (PaaS) is developed by developers for developers. Of course they’re going to love it.
It enables them to focus on the nuances of their applications — not on the day-to-day pointless activities that so often take their time away from solving real problems.</description></item></channel></rss>