<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Iot on Mark Chmarny</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/tags/iot/</link><description>Recent content in Iot on Mark Chmarny</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>Mark Chmarny</managingEditor><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 12:41:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.chmarny.com/tags/iot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using Flick buttons with Cloud Run on GCP</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/using-flick-buttons-with-cloud-run-on-gcp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 12:41:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/using-flick-buttons-with-cloud-run-on-gcp/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A co-worker recently told me about &lt;a href="https://flic.io/"&gt;flic.io&lt;/a&gt; buttons. These button caught my attention because they can include triggers for single, double, or hold click and can be easily wired up to all kinds of actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I instantly thought of of a few really interesting applications. To start with though, I wanted to create a simple service that would allow me to push the custom data defined on each button over HTTP to Cloud PubSub. That in turn would then connect me to the many more actuation options through GCP APIs and services that connect to Cloud PugSub.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Data Exchange — How to Amplify Value of Machine Data</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/data-exchange-how-to-amplify-value-of-machine-data/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 13:33:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/data-exchange-how-to-amplify-value-of-machine-data/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation that goes along with this post is available &lt;a href="http://www.slideshare.net/MarkChmarny/machine-data-how-to-realize-and-amplify-its-value"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href="http://mark.chmarny.com/post/139001618764/service-not-volume-data-explosion-and-how-to"&gt;my last post&lt;/a&gt; I went over the value &lt;a href="http://mark.chmarny.com/post/139001618764/service-not-volume-data-explosion-and-how-to"&gt;cycle of machine generated data&lt;/a&gt;. In this post, I want to follow up with a few ideas on how to further amplify value of that data by expanding its context beyond the walls of owning organization, in a construct we came to know as Data Exchange, and list a few innovation opportunities in each one of these areas.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>