<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Gcp on Mark Chmarny</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/tags/gcp/</link><description>Recent content in Gcp on Mark Chmarny</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>Mark Chmarny</managingEditor><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 16:12:38 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.chmarny.com/tags/gcp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reproducible OpenID connect to GCR for GitHub Actions workflows using Terraform</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/reproducible-github-workflow-openid-connect-for-gcp-using-terraform/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 16:12:38 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/reproducible-github-workflow-openid-connect-for-gcp-using-terraform/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The recently introduced by GitHub support for &lt;a href="https://openid.net/connect/"&gt;OpenID Connect&lt;/a&gt; (OIDC) tokens in &lt;a href="https://github.com/features/actions"&gt;GitHub Actions&lt;/a&gt; allows workflows to mint new tokens and then exchange those tokens for short-lived OAuth 2.0 or JWT tokens. These tokens can be used to access and manage Cloud resources. This is all done without the need to store the traditional long-lived service account keys in a form of GitHub secrets.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Multi Region REST Service on GCP using GitHub Template</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/multi-region-rest-service-on-gcp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 15:43:56 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/multi-region-rest-service-on-gcp/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I learn best by doing. And recently, most of the projects I&amp;rsquo;ve been building are either REST or gRPC-base services deployed as container images into Cloud Run on GCP. That means that I increasingly find myself recreating a lot of the same infra and app deployment flows.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Using Flick buttons with Cloud Run on GCP</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/using-flick-buttons-with-cloud-run-on-gcp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 12:41:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/using-flick-buttons-with-cloud-run-on-gcp/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A co-worker recently told me about &lt;a href="https://flic.io/"&gt;flic.io&lt;/a&gt; buttons. These button caught my attention because they can include triggers for single, double, or hold click and can be easily wired up to all kinds of actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I instantly thought of of a few really interesting applications. To start with though, I wanted to create a simple service that would allow me to push the custom data defined on each button over HTTP to Cloud PubSub. That in turn would then connect me to the many more actuation options through GCP APIs and services that connect to Cloud PugSub.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How to use Stackdriver to monitor custom application metrics</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/how-to-use-stackdriver-to-monitor-custom-application-metrics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 22:08:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/how-to-use-stackdriver-to-monitor-custom-application-metrics/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/stackdriver/"&gt;Stackdriver&lt;/a&gt; has thousands of build-in metrics to monitor everything from Kubernetes cluster to database or storage. Stackdriver is also not just limited to Google Cloud Platform (GCP), it supports a number of AWS-native services and extensive log monitoring capabilities for a wide array of open source software packages, whether they run in the Cloud or in on premises.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Twitter Sentiment Analysis in Go using Google NLP API</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/twitter-sentiment-analysis-in-go-using-google-nlp/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 17:26:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/twitter-sentiment-analysis-in-go-using-google-nlp/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As part of my ramp up on Google APIs I wanted to create a &lt;a href="https://github.com/mchmarny/tfeel"&gt;project&lt;/a&gt; that would allow me some practical exercise in a context of a real application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://blog.chmarny.com/images/1__MV8vPEMdz5obDiBmZDECIg.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TFeel (short for Twitter Feeling) is a simple sentiment analyses over tweeter data for specific Twitter search terms using Google Cloud services:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My experience with Google Compute Engine</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/my-experience-with-google-compute-engine/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:36:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/my-experience-with-google-compute-engine/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As part of my recent solution review, I wanted to compare a few performance metrics specific to multi-node data service deployment on different clouds. This post is about my experience with Google Compute Engine (GCE) as part of that evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>