<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cve on Mark Chmarny</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/tags/cve/</link><description>Recent content in Cve on Mark Chmarny</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>Mark Chmarny</managingEditor><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 08:57:57 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.chmarny.com/tags/cve/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Provenance, transparency, and context, the three aspects of software supply chain security you can implement today</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/provenance-transparency-context-3-aspects-of-s3c-you-can-implement-today/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 08:57:57 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/provenance-transparency-context-3-aspects-of-s3c-you-can-implement-today/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The practice of Secure Software Supply Chain (S3C) can get complex at times. Fortunately though, a large portion of the key things we can do to secure our software delivery pipelines are actually pretty easy. This post covers three concepts you can implement today:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Software supply chain data fatigue and what I’ve learned from SBOM, vulnerability reports</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/automating-software-supply-chain-security/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 07:09:34 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/automating-software-supply-chain-security/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you are doing any vulnerability detection in your software release pipeline today, you are already familiar with the volumes of data these scanners can generate. That dataset gets significantly larger when you add things like license scanning and &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/sbom"&gt;Software Bill of Materials&lt;/a&gt; (SBOM) generation. That volume of data gets further compounded with each highly-automated pipeline you operate. This can quickly lead to what I refer to as a Software Supply Chain Security (S3C) data fatigue, as many vulnerabilities you’ll discover you simply can’t do anything about. There is an actionable signal in there actually, it’s just hard to find it in the midst of all the noise.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>