<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>conf on Mark Chmarny Blog</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/categories/conf/</link><description>Recent content in conf on Mark Chmarny Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 16:30:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.chmarny.com/categories/conf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Sessions at Google Next 2019</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/my-sessions-at-google-next-2019/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 16:30:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/my-sessions-at-google-next-2019/</guid><description>Next week, April 9–11, Google will be hosting this year’s Cloud Next Conference in San Francisco. The conference is already sold out, but there will be a livestream from keynotes and video available shortly after the sessions.
This year, we have a lot of content to share, and I have the privilege of presenting in four sessions — and hope to do at least six live demos.</description></item><item><title>Knative momentum continues…</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/knative-momentum-continues/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 19:02:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/knative-momentum-continues/</guid><description>I wrote a new post on Google blog on the momentum behind the Knative project. How it the community reached another adoption milestone, doubling the number of its contributors. Also, another data point underscoring the Knative momentum is the month-over-month contributions which have increased over 45% since the 0.</description></item><item><title>Knative at SpringOne</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/knative-at-springone/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 18:59:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/knative-at-springone/</guid><description>I had an opportunity to keynote at this year’s SpringOne conference in DC on Serverless, Kubernetes, and more specifically Knative.
I also covered the great work our open source team at Google been doing, making Spring 1st class citizen on Google Cloud Platform.</description></item><item><title>One Platform for Your Functions, Applications, and Containers</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/one-platform-for-your-functions-apps-and-containers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 22:25:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/one-platform-for-your-functions-apps-and-containers/</guid><description>Video from the session Ville and I gave at Google Cloud Next 2018. The slides as well as the repo containing all the demos I used in this at https://github.com/mchmarny/next18</description></item><item><title>Few quick notes from Google Next 2017</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/notes-from-google-next-2017/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 15:45:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/notes-from-google-next-2017/</guid><description>I had the opportunity to attend Google Next this year. Week after this event I joined Google. Here are some quick notes in no particular order:
Registration was a pain, long lines. My first tech conference where I had to go through a metal detector.</description></item></channel></rss>