<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Db on Mark Chmarny</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/tags/db/</link><description>Recent content in Db on Mark Chmarny</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>Mark Chmarny</managingEditor><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:26:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.chmarny.com/tags/db/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Don't use yesterday's database to develop tomorrow's solutions</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/dont-use-yesterday-database-to-develop-tomorrow-solutions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:26:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/dont-use-yesterday-database-to-develop-tomorrow-solutions/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We are in a midst of drastic shift in application development landscape. Developers entering the market today use different tools and follow different patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the core patterns of on-line application development today is cloud scale design. While traditionally architectures would rely on more powerful servers, today, that approach simply does not scale. We have reached that point where, in many cases, there are no powerful enough servers, or their cost would be prohibitive. Considering the unpredictable usage patterns today’s on-line applications also must be flexible to address demand spikes and assure efficient service during low utilization.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Time series data management using InfluxDB</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/time-series-data-management-using-influxdb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 00:41:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/time-series-data-management-using-influxdb/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;After a pretty positive experience with &lt;a href="http://influxdb.com&amp;amp;t=MDNmNjA2NmIwNTkxYjUzNDg0YzY2NTUwNmJmMjAzNjkzOGY0ZjFjNCxjclJsVjdENA%3D%3D"&gt;influxdb&lt;/a&gt; I wanted to create a super simple telemetry producer (this one in Node.js) to spotlight a few types of time series data query supported in influxdb. (Source code available on &lt;a href="https://github.com/mchmarny/timeseries-samples&amp;amp;t=Nzk1NjkzYWI3ZDU1OGUzYTg3YmY4MjBkMzE5ZDlmNjk2ODc2NmMzYixjclJsVjdENA%3D%3D"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://blog.chmarny.com/images/0__bqylsNDJDNtWuTyx.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get live data for this demo, I created a simple script that generates metric data for CPU Utilization and Free Memory on your local machine at 1 sec resolution.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>