<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>opinion on Mark Chmarny Blog</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/categories/opinion/</link><description>Recent content in opinion on Mark Chmarny Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 19:35:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.chmarny.com/categories/opinion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Complexity can be learned but abstractions come at a long-term cost</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/complexity-can-be-learned-but-abstractions-come-at-long-term-cost/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 19:35:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/complexity-can-be-learned-but-abstractions-come-at-long-term-cost/</guid><description>All complexity needs to be abstracted, right? This reductionist statements misses nuance around the inherent cost/benefit tradeoffs, especially when you consider these over time.
Don’t get me wrong, there often are good reasons for additional layers to make things simpler (grow adoption, lowering toil, removing friction, etc.</description></item><item><title>Renaissance of custom vertical solution</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/renaissance-of-custom-vertical-solution/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 18:49:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/renaissance-of-custom-vertical-solution/</guid><description>We are entering a period where custom, highly-optimized, vertical solutions are becoming viable option again. This is a good news for ISVs with proven domain expertise and skilled development resources.
Why do I think so? We now have:
Plethora of feature-rich developer frameworks, message queues, scalable data stores, and even lower-level components in the OSS community with great documentation and a large number of use-case validation Growing number of custom solution companies (more than just ISVs) with existing deep vertical/domain expertise who are also increasingly now investing in hiring and training strong development teams Virtually every Cloud provider offering either a raw Kubernetes service or managed container execution platform which (regardless how you feel about these technologies) creates ubiquitous surface area that can be addressed with a single solution Yes, there still are many ways in which these custom development efforts can fail.</description></item><item><title>Few quick notes from Google Next 2017</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/notes-from-google-next-2017/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 15:45:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/notes-from-google-next-2017/</guid><description>I had the opportunity to attend Google Next this year. Week after this event I joined Google. Here are some quick notes in no particular order:
Registration was a pain, long lines. My first tech conference where I had to go through a metal detector.</description></item><item><title>Service, not Volume - data explosion and how to amplify its value</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/service-not-volume-data-explosion-and-how-to-amplify-its-value/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 00:46:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/service-not-volume-data-explosion-and-how-to-amplify-its-value/</guid><description>Data is growing at an exponential pace. Based on recent numbers from IDC, the total amount of data in 2015 (4.4ZB) will grow to 44ZB in 2020. Franky, how much is in Zettabyte is almost inconsequential. It is the fact that all of the data generated since the beginning of time (at least the electronic part), will grow 10x in just the next four years that’s shocking!</description></item><item><title>Data Exchange — How to Amplify Value of Machine Data</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/data-exchange-how-to-amplify-value-of-machine-data/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 13:33:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/data-exchange-how-to-amplify-value-of-machine-data/</guid><description>The presentation that goes along with this post is available here
In my last post I went over the value cycle of machine generated data. In this post, I want to follow up with a few ideas on how to further amplify value of that data by expanding its context beyond the walls of owning organization, in a construct we came to know as Data Exchange, and list a few innovation opportunities in each one of these areas.</description></item><item><title>Vision of smarter thingz; project in adaptive metric flow modeling</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/vision-of-smarter-thingz-project-in-adaptive-metric-flow-modeling/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:43:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/vision-of-smarter-thingz-project-in-adaptive-metric-flow-modeling/</guid><description>Over the holidays, as many of us do, I embarked on a little extra-curriculum development effort I called thingz.io. I was driven by the pattern I’d observed in Data Center (DC) monitoring products; although that pattern also exists in many of today’s Internet of Things (IoT) solutions.</description></item><item><title>Smaller, single-purpose, atomic functions core ingredient of tomorrow’s computing</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/smaller-single-purpose-atomic-functions-core-ingredient-of-tomorrow-computing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:40:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/smaller-single-purpose-atomic-functions-core-ingredient-of-tomorrow-computing/</guid><description>Last week I had a chance to attend the 3rd AWS re:invent conference in Vegas. I’m not a big fan of that city myself, but, as in previous years, re:invent has not disappointed.
Much coverage has been dedicated to the newly introduced services; I won’t bore you with that.</description></item><item><title>Intel doubles down on open, easier to use, and performance-optimized Hadoop</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/intel-doubles-down-on-its-vision-of-open-performance-optimized-hadoop/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:38:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/intel-doubles-down-on-its-vision-of-open-performance-optimized-hadoop/</guid><description>Over eight months ago, I joined Intel to work on their next-generation data analytics platform. In large, my decision was based on Intel’s desire to address the “voodoo magic” in Big Data: the complexities that require deep technical skills which are preventing domain experts from gaining access to large volumes of data.</description></item><item><title>HDFS has won, now de facto standard for centralized data storage</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/hdfs-has-won-de-facto-standard-for-centralized-data-storage/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:28:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/hdfs-has-won-de-facto-standard-for-centralized-data-storage/</guid><description>The “high-priests” of Big Data have spoken. Hadoop Distributed File System (HDFS) is now the de facto standard platform for data storage. You may have heard this “heresy” uttered before. But, for me, it wasn’t until the recent Strata conference that I began to really understand how prevalent this opinion actually is.</description></item><item><title>Don't use yesterday's database to develop tomorrow's solutions</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/dont-use-yesterday-database-to-develop-tomorrow-solutions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:26:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/dont-use-yesterday-database-to-develop-tomorrow-solutions/</guid><description>We are in a midst of drastic shift in application development landscape. Developers entering the market today use different tools and follow different patterns.
One of the core patterns of on-line application development today is cloud scale design. While traditionally architectures would rely on more powerful servers, today, that approach simply does not scale.</description></item><item><title>Data Scientists are developers; their tools just suck</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/data-scientists-are-developers-too-their-tools-just-suck/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 03:05:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/data-scientists-are-developers-too-their-tools-just-suck/</guid><description>Data science is not a new discipline. In some sense it even pre-dates application development. You wouldn’t know that by looking at the average enterprise nowadays.
The popular perception is that enterprises today struggle to deliver any tangible value from Big Data.</description></item><item><title>Gluttony of great open ML tools too hard for enterprise to use</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/gluttony-of-open-machine-intelligence-software-enterprise-finds-hard-to-use/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 11:40:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/gluttony-of-open-machine-intelligence-software-enterprise-finds-hard-to-use/</guid><description>Seems like every week we hear about yet another new open source Machine/Deep Learning library or Analytical Framework.
Talking to people at Strata this week only confirmed for me that in the midst of what can only be described as virtual gluttony of open-source software, there is massive number of organizations who find it increasingly harder to implement these technologies.</description></item><item><title>Federated not Balkanized - The Future of Data and Its Short-term Cloud Challenges</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/federated-not-balkanized-future-of-data-and-cloud-challenges/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 00:06:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/federated-not-balkanized-future-of-data-and-cloud-challenges/</guid><description>As a long-term Cloud storage user I recently wanted to re-evaluate my options. New content management providers became available and I wanted to make sure I wasn’t missing on the new shinny tech out there.
As I was considering the pros and cons of each option, I realized the apparent shift in my personal attitude towards cloud data storage over last few years.</description></item><item><title>Data Opportunities, 3 Areas to Focus Innovation</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/data-opportunities-3-areas-to-focus-innovation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 00:33:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/data-opportunities-3-areas-to-focus-innovation/</guid><description>About a year and a half ago, I wrote about Big Data Opportunities, focusing primarily on Leveraging Unused Data, Driving New Value From Summary Data and Harnessing Heterogeneous Data Sensors (more recently known as Internet of Things).
Since that post, data space has exploded with numerous solutions addressing many of these areas.</description></item></channel></rss>