<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cloud on Mark Chmarny Blog</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/categories/cloud/</link><description>Recent content in cloud on Mark Chmarny Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 22:10:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.chmarny.com/categories/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to run containerized workloads in GCE VM</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/how-to-run-containerized-workloads-in-gce-vm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 22:10:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/how-to-run-containerized-workloads-in-gce-vm/</guid><description>While the idea of a serverless platform and long running workloads does seem somewhat “unnatural” at first, smart people are already working on that (looking at you @Knative community). In the meantime, a simple approach is sometimes all you may need.</description></item><item><title>Using Flick buttons with Cloud Run on GCP</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/using-flick-buttons-with-cloud-run-on-gcp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 12:41:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/using-flick-buttons-with-cloud-run-on-gcp/</guid><description>A co-worker recently told me about flic.io buttons. These button caught my attention because they can include triggers for single, double, or hold click and can be easily wired up to all kinds of actions.
I instantly thought of of a few really interesting applications.</description></item><item><title>How to use Stackdriver to monitor custom application metrics</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/how-to-use-stackdriver-to-monitor-custom-application-metrics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 22:08:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/how-to-use-stackdriver-to-monitor-custom-application-metrics/</guid><description>Google Stackdriver has thousands of build-in metrics to monitor everything from Kubernetes cluster to database or storage. Stackdriver is also not just limited to Google Cloud Platform (GCP), it supports a number of AWS-native services and extensive log monitoring capabilities for a wide array of open source software packages, whether they run in the Cloud or in on premises.</description></item><item><title>Using Google Cloud Spanner to measure social media influence over stock market</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/using-google-cloud-spanner-to-measure-social-media-influence-over-stock-market/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 15:51:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/using-google-cloud-spanner-to-measure-social-media-influence-over-stock-market/</guid><description>I wanted to use the now generally available Cloud Spanner database to write an app that would track stock prices and social media sentiment to identify potential correlation.
To test even the validity of this approach I put together a Go app that subscribes to Twitter stream for all companies defined in the Stocks table and scores each event against the Google NLP API while comparing the user sentiment against the stock ask price against Yahoo API.</description></item><item><title>Vision of smarter thingz; project in adaptive metric flow modeling</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/vision-of-smarter-thingz-project-in-adaptive-metric-flow-modeling/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:43:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/vision-of-smarter-thingz-project-in-adaptive-metric-flow-modeling/</guid><description>Over the holidays, as many of us do, I embarked on a little extra-curriculum development effort I called thingz.io. I was driven by the pattern I’d observed in Data Center (DC) monitoring products; although that pattern also exists in many of today’s Internet of Things (IoT) solutions.</description></item><item><title>Smaller, single-purpose, atomic functions core ingredient of tomorrow’s computing</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/smaller-single-purpose-atomic-functions-core-ingredient-of-tomorrow-computing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:40:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/smaller-single-purpose-atomic-functions-core-ingredient-of-tomorrow-computing/</guid><description>Last week I had a chance to attend the 3rd AWS re:invent conference in Vegas. I’m not a big fan of that city myself, but, as in previous years, re:invent has not disappointed.
Much coverage has been dedicated to the newly introduced services; I won’t bore you with that.</description></item><item><title>My experience with Google Compute Engine</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/my-experience-with-google-compute-engine/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:36:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/my-experience-with-google-compute-engine/</guid><description>As part of my recent solution review, I wanted to compare a few performance metrics specific to multi-node data service deployment on different clouds. This post is about my experience with Google Compute Engine (GCE) as part of that evaluation.</description></item><item><title>Data-related investments shift from tech to skills — talent new differentiator</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/data-related-investments-shift-from-tech-to-skills-talent-new-differentiator/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:24:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/data-related-investments-shift-from-tech-to-skills-talent-new-differentiator/</guid><description>Over the last decade, the access to best-of-bread data technologies has become easier. This is due mainly to the increasing popularity of open source software (OSS). While this phenomenon holds true in other areas like operating systems, application servers, development frameworks or even monitoring tools, it is perhaps most prevalent in the area of data.</description></item><item><title>Federated not Balkanized - The Future of Data and Its Short-term Cloud Challenges</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/federated-not-balkanized-future-of-data-and-cloud-challenges/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 00:06:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/federated-not-balkanized-future-of-data-and-cloud-challenges/</guid><description>As a long-term Cloud storage user I recently wanted to re-evaluate my options. New content management providers became available and I wanted to make sure I wasn’t missing on the new shinny tech out there.
As I was considering the pros and cons of each option, I realized the apparent shift in my personal attitude towards cloud data storage over last few years.</description></item></channel></rss>