<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tech on Mark Chmarny</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/categories/tech/</link><description>Recent content in Tech on Mark Chmarny</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>Mark Chmarny</managingEditor><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 19:12:38 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.chmarny.com/categories/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Leaving Cruise; why I'm still excited about AI platforms</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/leaving-cruise/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 19:12:38 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/leaving-cruise/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today marks a bittersweet moment as I say goodbye to &lt;a href="https://getcruise.com"&gt;Cruise&lt;/a&gt;. When I joined the company seven months ago, my mission was to scale the AV services worldwide and to modernize the AV and Cloud service developer platforms. Despite the unexpected challenges following the &lt;a href="https://getcruise.com/news/blog/2024/cruise-releases-third-party-findings-regarding-october-2/"&gt;October incident&lt;/a&gt;, my journey at Cruise has been incredibly enriching, teaching me the true essence of resilience, adaptability, and commitment to excellence.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Twitter follower status monitoring made easy using TweeThingz</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/twitter-follower-activity-monitoring-using-tweethingz/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 09:13:38 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/twitter-follower-activity-monitoring-using-tweethingz/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align="right" src="https://blog.chmarny.com/images/twitter-api-access.jpeg" style="width:300px; height:auto; margin:20px" /&gt;Twitter does provide notifications for when new users start following you. It does now however provide any notifications when users stop following you. Now, there is an ample of web sites out there who do provide that service, in most cases though, they cost money, and ask you for a complete access to your Twitter account.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Complexity can be learned but abstractions come at a long-term cost</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/complexity-can-be-learned-but-abstractions-come-at-long-term-cost/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 19:35:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/complexity-can-be-learned-but-abstractions-come-at-long-term-cost/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;All complexity needs to be abstracted, right? This reductionist statements misses nuance around the inherent cost/benefit tradeoffs, especially when you consider these over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong, there often are good reasons for additional layers to make things simpler (grow adoption, lowering toil, removing friction, etc.). Still, these layers come at the long-term cost that’s often is not a part of the evaluation process.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Renaissance of custom vertical solution</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/renaissance-of-custom-vertical-solution/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 18:49:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/renaissance-of-custom-vertical-solution/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We are entering a period where custom, highly-optimized, vertical solutions are becoming viable option again. This is a good news for ISVs with proven domain expertise and skilled development resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do I think so? We now have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plethora of feature-rich developer frameworks, message queues, scalable data stores, and even lower-level components in the OSS community with great documentation and a large number of use-case validation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Growing number of custom solution companies (more than just ISVs) with existing deep vertical/domain expertise who are also increasingly now investing in hiring and training strong development teams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Virtually every Cloud provider offering either a raw Kubernetes service or managed container execution platform which (regardless how you feel about these technologies) creates ubiquitous surface area that can be addressed with a single solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, there still are many ways in which these custom development efforts can fail. Still, as one who has started their professional career developing custom software, I’m glad to see how these kinds of efforts are becoming cost effective again and increasingly represent a viable option for differentiation and real business value delivery.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Few quick notes from Google Next 2017</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/notes-from-google-next-2017/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 15:45:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/notes-from-google-next-2017/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I had the opportunity to attend Google Next this year. Week after this event I joined Google. Here are some quick notes in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Registration was a pain, long lines. My first tech conference where I had to go through a metal detector.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Impressive reminder of the core tech underlining Google Cloud (i.e. &lt;a href="https://static.googleusercontent.com/media/research.google.com/en//pubs/archive/43438.pdf"&gt;Borg&lt;/a&gt;) and Google’s experience in operating at scale.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serious commitment to ML and Data Science: invest in talent/community (&lt;a href="https://www.kaggle.com/"&gt;Kaggle&lt;/a&gt;), vision/leadership (&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Rgqgdddl018"&gt;Fei-Fei Li keynote&lt;/a&gt;), powerful &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/products/machine-learning/"&gt;APIs&lt;/a&gt; (i.e. Label/Face Detection, OCR, Explicit Content etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feels like the ease of use for Google is more important than time time market (see the above DS APIs but also Spanner UX).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clear understanding of data economy’s potential value (goes with the scale comment but the experience was apparent in many sessions/keynotes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open/partner market makes stronger platform (&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h9FSqVbdHis&amp;amp;index=7&amp;amp;list=PLIivdWyY5sqI8RuUibiH8sMb1ExIw0lAR"&gt;Sam Ramji’s keynote&lt;/a&gt; drilled on this best), early hints of this were probably the main reason why I wanted to join Google Cloud team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Size/quality of the network (both, cables &amp;amp; tech), globally distributed data systems (specifically latency) are perhaps the best example of the user value here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Service, not Volume - data explosion and how to amplify its value</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/service-not-volume-data-explosion-and-how-to-amplify-its-value/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 00:46:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/service-not-volume-data-explosion-and-how-to-amplify-its-value/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Data is growing at an &lt;a href="https://web-assets.domo.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/15_domo_data-never-sleeps-3_final1.png"&gt;exponential pace&lt;/a&gt;. Based on recent numbers from &lt;a href="http://www.computerweekly.com/news/2240217788/Data-set-to-grow-10-fold-by-2020-as-internet-of-things-takes-off"&gt;IDC&lt;/a&gt;, the total amount of data in 2015 (4.4ZB) will grow to 44ZB in 2020. Franky, how much is in &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zettabyte&amp;amp;t=YmJkMzIzNDU5ZWI0ZGQzNWQ3ZTRkNGZlZmJkY2RiZmE4OTk2ZGM2YixtZ05JVTNVbA%3D%3D"&gt;Zettabyte&lt;/a&gt; is almost inconsequential. It is the fact that all of the data generated since the beginning of time (at least the electronic part), will grow 10x in just the next four years that’s shocking!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Data Exchange — How to Amplify Value of Machine Data</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/data-exchange-how-to-amplify-value-of-machine-data/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 13:33:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/data-exchange-how-to-amplify-value-of-machine-data/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation that goes along with this post is available &lt;a href="http://www.slideshare.net/MarkChmarny/machine-data-how-to-realize-and-amplify-its-value"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href="http://mark.chmarny.com/post/139001618764/service-not-volume-data-explosion-and-how-to"&gt;my last post&lt;/a&gt; I went over the value &lt;a href="http://mark.chmarny.com/post/139001618764/service-not-volume-data-explosion-and-how-to"&gt;cycle of machine generated data&lt;/a&gt;. In this post, I want to follow up with a few ideas on how to further amplify value of that data by expanding its context beyond the walls of owning organization, in a construct we came to know as Data Exchange, and list a few innovation opportunities in each one of these areas.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>HDFS has won, now de facto standard for centralized data storage</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/hdfs-has-won-de-facto-standard-for-centralized-data-storage/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:28:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/hdfs-has-won-de-facto-standard-for-centralized-data-storage/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;high-priests&amp;rdquo; of Big Data have spoken. Hadoop Distributed File System (&lt;a href="http://hadoop.apache.org/docs/hdfs/current/hdfs_design.html&amp;amp;t=ZjcxYWQyNjE5NTI5MjVjMGIyZDlhYTgwZDQ1ZmJkOWNiNjEwMjJiMixOSG5XdzVSRA%3D%3D"&gt;HDFS&lt;/a&gt;) is now the de facto standard platform for data storage. You may have heard this &amp;ldquo;heresy&amp;rdquo; uttered before. But, for me, it wasn’t until the recent &lt;a href="http://mark.chmarny.com/2012/10/stratahadoop-world-2012-etl-sql-other.html"&gt;Strata conference&lt;/a&gt; that I began to really understand how prevalent this opinion actually is.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Don't use yesterday's database to develop tomorrow's solutions</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/dont-use-yesterday-database-to-develop-tomorrow-solutions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:26:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/dont-use-yesterday-database-to-develop-tomorrow-solutions/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We are in a midst of drastic shift in application development landscape. Developers entering the market today use different tools and follow different patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the core patterns of on-line application development today is cloud scale design. While traditionally architectures would rely on more powerful servers, today, that approach simply does not scale. We have reached that point where, in many cases, there are no powerful enough servers, or their cost would be prohibitive. Considering the unpredictable usage patterns today’s on-line applications also must be flexible to address demand spikes and assure efficient service during low utilization.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Data-related investments shift from tech to skills — talent new differentiator</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/data-related-investments-shift-from-tech-to-skills-talent-new-differentiator/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:24:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/data-related-investments-shift-from-tech-to-skills-talent-new-differentiator/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last decade, the access to best-of-bread data technologies has become easier. This is due mainly to the increasing popularity of open source software (OSS). While this phenomenon holds true in other areas like operating systems, application servers, development frameworks or even monitoring tools, it is perhaps most prevalent in the area of data.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Intel doubles down on open, easier to use, and performance-optimized Hadoop</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/intel-doubles-down-on-its-vision-of-open-performance-optimized-hadoop/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 00:38:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/intel-doubles-down-on-its-vision-of-open-performance-optimized-hadoop/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Over eight months ago, &lt;a href="https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/thinking-big-about-data-at-intel.md"&gt;I joined Intel to work on their next-generation data analytics platform&lt;/a&gt;. In large, my decision was based on Intel’s desire to address the &amp;ldquo;voodoo magic&amp;rdquo; in Big Data: the complexities that require deep technical skills which are preventing domain experts from gaining access to large volumes of data. The idea was that by leveraging the distributed data processing capabilities of &lt;a href="http://hadoop.apache.org/&amp;amp;t=ODQwMzljZTFhMjE4MzZlNjUxNWQ5ZjFhYjE2Y2MwOGE1OGE4YzFmNSxaVU4zS00wOQ%3D%3D"&gt;Apache Hadoop&lt;/a&gt;, and combining them with Intel’s breadth of infrastructure experience, we could make Big Data analytics more accessible and therefore more prevalent.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Smaller, single-purpose, atomic functions core ingredient of tomorrow’s computing</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/smaller-single-purpose-atomic-functions-core-ingredient-of-tomorrow-computing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:40:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/smaller-single-purpose-atomic-functions-core-ingredient-of-tomorrow-computing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I had a chance to attend the 3rd AWS re:invent conference in Vegas. I’m not a big fan of that city myself, but, as in previous years, re:invent has not disappointed. Much coverage has been dedicated to the newly introduced services; I won’t bore you with that. Instead, I wanted to share with you a few higher-level thoughts I captured at the event.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gluttony of great open ML tools too hard for enterprise to use</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/gluttony-of-open-machine-intelligence-software-enterprise-finds-hard-to-use/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 11:40:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/gluttony-of-open-machine-intelligence-software-enterprise-finds-hard-to-use/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Seems like every week we hear about yet another new open source Machine/Deep Learning library or Analytical Framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talking to people at &lt;a href="http://conferences.oreilly.com/strata/hadoop-big-data-eu"&gt;Strata this week&lt;/a&gt; only confirmed for me that in the midst of what can only be described as virtual gluttony of open-source software, there is massive number of organizations who find it increasingly harder to implement these technologies. Even the task of identifying the right solution can overwhelm many, and result in a tailspin of endless use-case/feature comparison.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Federated not Balkanized - The Future of Data and Its Short-term Cloud Challenges</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/federated-not-balkanized-future-of-data-and-cloud-challenges/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 00:06:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/federated-not-balkanized-future-of-data-and-cloud-challenges/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As a long-term Cloud storage user I recently wanted to re-evaluate my options. New content management providers became available and I wanted to make sure I wasn’t missing on the new shinny tech out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was considering the pros and cons of each option, I realized the apparent shift in my personal attitude towards cloud data storage over last few years. My concerns used to be solely with security. Now, while the data security is still critical, I am much more interested in data access, ownership, integration and its control.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Data Opportunities, 3 Areas to Focus Innovation</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/data-opportunities-3-areas-to-focus-innovation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 00:33:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/data-opportunities-3-areas-to-focus-innovation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;About a year and a half ago, I wrote about &lt;a href="https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/3-killer-big-data-app-opportunities.md"&gt;Big Data Opportunities&lt;/a&gt;, focusing primarily on Leveraging Unused Data, Driving New Value From Summary Data and Harnessing Heterogeneous Data Sensors (more recently known as &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_of_things"&gt;Internet of Things&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://blog.chmarny.com/images/0__FnPtGrT0LSmX6DBG.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since that post, data space has exploded with numerous solutions addressing many of these areas. These solutions while mostly based on batch operations and limited to serial MapReduce jobs against frequently off-line, inadequately secured, Hadoop cluster, they do allow access to previously inaccessible data.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>PaaS not just about runtime, data services are the next differentiator</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/paas-not-just-about-runtime-data-services-are-the-next-differentiator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:30:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/paas-not-just-about-runtime-data-services-are-the-next-differentiator/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In general, Platform as a Service (&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Platform_as_a_service&amp;amp;t=YzdiYWU1Yjc0MTdkMzZiMzM3N2NjN2I0MTNmMDk0ZDhlYTBiNzk1YixZY0ltODJRaQ%3D%3D"&gt;PaaS&lt;/a&gt;) is developed by developers for developers. Of course &lt;a href="http://www.informationweek.com/cloud-computing/platform/vmwares-cloud-foundry-ranked-top-develop/232200211&amp;amp;t=ZTE3MjQyYzA0ODc4ZTQ2M2ExZjRmZGYwODJiNWJlN2M3OGY1ZWE1YyxZY0ltODJRaQ%3D%3D"&gt;they’re going to love it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It enables them to focus on the nuances of their applications — not on the day-to-day pointless activities that so often take their time away from solving real problems.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>