<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Knative on Mark Chmarny</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/tags/knative/</link><description>Recent content in Knative on Mark Chmarny</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>Mark Chmarny</managingEditor><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 16:30:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.chmarny.com/tags/knative/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Sessions at Google Next 2019</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/my-sessions-at-google-next-2019/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 16:30:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/my-sessions-at-google-next-2019/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Next week, April 9–11, Google will be hosting this year’s &lt;a href="https://cloud.withgoogle.com/next/sf"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cloud Next Conference&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in San Francisco. The conference is already sold out, but there will be a &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/WPfyjzgBEJU%29%20youtu.be/WPfyjzgBEJU"&gt;livestream&lt;/a&gt; from keynotes and video available shortly after the sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, we have a lot of content to share, and I have the privilege of presenting in &lt;a href="https://cloud.withgoogle.com/next/sf/speakers?speaker=2278AB79A813FD48"&gt;four sessions&lt;/a&gt; — and hope to do at least six live demos.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Knative - Serverless on Your Own Terms</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/knative-serverless-on-your-own-terms/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 02:42:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/knative-serverless-on-your-own-terms/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I had a chance to speak at the Cloud Conf 2019 in Turin, Italy. The conference has double its audience from last year, had a spectacular venue, and large selection of topics. I spoke in the #serverless track on using Knative as a means to serverless where you want it and on your own terms. Stressing the importance of portability and demonstrating the key features that the Kantive community has already delivered.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My Keynote at SpringOne</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/my-keynote-at-springone/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 18:59:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/my-keynote-at-springone/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I had an opportunity to keynote at this year’s &lt;a href="https://springoneplatform.io/2018/speakers/mark-chmarny"&gt;SpringOne&lt;/a&gt; conference in DC on Serverless, &lt;a href="https://kubernetes.io/"&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;, and more specifically &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/knative/"&gt;Knative&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EKmp9xbKiso" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also covered the great work our open source team at Google been doing, making Spring 1st class citizen on &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/"&gt;Google Cloud Platform&lt;/a&gt;. On a personal level, it was good to reconnect with some old friends from &lt;a href="https://pivotal.io/"&gt;Pivotal&lt;/a&gt;, and, community at large.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Build and manage modern serverless workloads using Knative on Kubernetes</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/build-modern-serverless-workloads-using-knative-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 16:05:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/build-modern-serverless-workloads-using-knative-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;By now, &lt;a href="https://kubernetes.io/"&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; should be the default target for your deployments. Yes, there are still use-cases where Kubernetes is not the optimal choice, but these represent an increasingly smaller number of modern workloads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main value of Kubernetes is that it greatly abstracts much of the infrastructure management pain. The broad support amongst virtually all major Cloud Service Providers (CSP) also means that your workloads are portable. Combined with the already vibrant ecosystem of Kubernetes-related tools, means that the experience of the operator, the person responsible for managing Kubernetes, is now pretty smooth.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Few quick notes from Google Next 2017</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/notes-from-google-next-2017/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 15:45:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/notes-from-google-next-2017/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I had the opportunity to attend Google Next this year. Week after this event I joined Google. Here are some quick notes in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Registration was a pain, long lines. My first tech conference where I had to go through a metal detector.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Impressive reminder of the core tech underlining Google Cloud (i.e. &lt;a href="https://static.googleusercontent.com/media/research.google.com/en//pubs/archive/43438.pdf"&gt;Borg&lt;/a&gt;) and Google’s experience in operating at scale.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serious commitment to ML and Data Science: invest in talent/community (&lt;a href="https://www.kaggle.com/"&gt;Kaggle&lt;/a&gt;), vision/leadership (&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Rgqgdddl018"&gt;Fei-Fei Li keynote&lt;/a&gt;), powerful &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/products/machine-learning/"&gt;APIs&lt;/a&gt; (i.e. Label/Face Detection, OCR, Explicit Content etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feels like the ease of use for Google is more important than time time market (see the above DS APIs but also Spanner UX).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clear understanding of data economy’s potential value (goes with the scale comment but the experience was apparent in many sessions/keynotes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open/partner market makes stronger platform (&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h9FSqVbdHis&amp;amp;index=7&amp;amp;list=PLIivdWyY5sqI8RuUibiH8sMb1ExIw0lAR"&gt;Sam Ramji’s keynote&lt;/a&gt; drilled on this best), early hints of this were probably the main reason why I wanted to join Google Cloud team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Size/quality of the network (both, cables &amp;amp; tech), globally distributed data systems (specifically latency) are perhaps the best example of the user value here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Smaller, single-purpose, atomic functions core ingredient of tomorrow’s computing</title><link>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/smaller-single-purpose-atomic-functions-core-ingredient-of-tomorrow-computing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:40:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.chmarny.com/posts/smaller-single-purpose-atomic-functions-core-ingredient-of-tomorrow-computing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I had a chance to attend the 3rd AWS re:invent conference in Vegas. I’m not a big fan of that city myself, but, as in previous years, re:invent has not disappointed. Much coverage has been dedicated to the newly introduced services; I won’t bore you with that. Instead, I wanted to share with you a few higher-level thoughts I captured at the event.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>